<biblScope>4</biblScope>

and passion, or by undue correction, kill his own slave, or the slave of another person, he shall forfeit 350l. currency," or 50l. sterling. The thirty-eighth and thirty-ninth clauses are conceived in a similar spirit.<p>
<p>Fourteen pound (we are not told whether this be currency or sterling, but it matters little,) is the penalty for "cutting out the tongue, dismembering, and other tortures inflicted by any other instrument than a horsewhip, cowskin, or small stick." <interp key="I believe this to be true because on the timeline of the evolution of the treatment of slaves, the article cites that 1740 was the year Carolina prohibited the torture being described in the text. It is worth nothing that Hall was speaking about this in his time 1821-1871, which means the law had stood for a few decades, and had relevance to a certain degree, for him to be discussing it and the ramifications of its violation. However, I’m not sure if the financial penalties were executed as he explained." n="citation" cert="medium" ref=" https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treatment_of_slaves_in_the_United_States"> </interp>
There is, it is true, a semblance of humanity in the provision which follows, and which enacts, that the master of a slave shall be presumed guilty when his slave is maimed or cruelly beaten; but the whole effect of the clause is destroyed by ordering, that if he should not be able to clear himself of the imputation "by evidence," he may clear himself of it, "by making oath to the contrary." This is holding out a premium for perjury.<p>
<p>By the forty-third clause, any White man meeting above seven slaves on a high road together, shall and may whip each f them, not exceeding twenty lashes on the bare back. And by the fourth-fifth clause a penalty of 100l currency is inflicted for the crime of teaching a slave to write.<p>
<p>It would be difficult to account for the wanton and superflous barbarity which is exhibited in these and similar enactments, if we were not to resort, for an explanation of the phenomenon, to the powerful operation, in the breast of masters, of that basest and most cruel of all passions - fear. In this view of the subject, Mr. Hall<persName key="Hall, Charles" from="1821" to="1871" role="explorer" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Francis_Hall"> </persName> seems to concur; for he thus closes his account of the slave laws of Carolina<placeName key="Charleston, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=32_46_34_N_79_56_16_W> </placeName>: -<p>
<p>"Such is the code by which Christians govern Christians: nor is it, in any point, a dead letter. The fears of the proprietors are tremblingly alive, and racked with the dread of insurrection, in which they must expect the measure they have meted. A military police is constantly kept up in Charleston; and every Man of Colour, whether slave or free, found in the streets after dark, without a pass, is taken up and punished." Hall, p. 424<p>
<p>But we have scarcely occasion to resort to this principle, in order to account for the practical atrocities of the slave system. The </p>

















</body></text></TEI></teiCorpus>
